

2/160 Chapel Street St Kilda, 3182 **0431 520 122** perron.alex@gmail.com

I have spent the last 10 years working with Frederic's Kitchen, consistently looking for opportunities to take on more responsibility and grow my skillset, early on I had the fortunate ability to take over the company and implement my vision for its growth.

I have enjoy my tenure at Frederic's Kitchen and have learnt a tremendous amount in Business Management, Development, Marketing and Production/Operations.

The skills I have learnt can be translated to any practice and I'm now looking for an opportunity to refine on my technical skills.

I enjoy working on products and managing both the business' needs as well as the clients. I now look to move to a different industry with a wider range of challenges wanting to learn from and work with a diverse team, and be exposed to new and interesting forms of business and product management.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Director of Operations**

Frederic's Kitchen 2010 - present

My new role required me to now think long term and create a strategy to grow the business. My ability to listen and collaborate allowed me to both create a new product in an previously non-existent marketplace and continually expand successfully in this space.

#### Management:

- With the business stabilised I turned the leadership team's focus to expanding the operation.
- I realigned job roles to emphasise employees skill sets.
- Continue to manage and analyse P&L reports monthly and focus on create a healthy Gross Profit allowing more room for development and change.

#### Rebranding:

- In partnership with a marketing agency I executed a full rebrand of Frederic's Kitchen including logo design, new website and production of new marketing materials.
- This required collaboration in an field I was not an expert in and allowed me to listen and learn from some of the best in the industry.

#### R&D:

- I led the team in developing a new system to be able to freeze and store our products for long periods of time without sacrificing in quality.
- I worked closely with cross-functional teams to ensure we kept to our timeline.
- This led to us being able to create a new product range and a new market.

#### New Product Range / Marketing:

- Our new product range saw an increase in turnover by 12% and improved our Gross Profit by 8%
- I then again worked with all department to create roadmaps for our new Variety Pack range.

- I led the marketing and sales team to understand market potential and best utilised customer feedback to organise changes in offering and how to adapt to a seasonal market
- Worked with Production in creating schedules to adapt with scaling growth.
- We began using new metrics and KPI's to determine the success of a products life cycle.

#### Expansion:

- Increase in sales required a further change in storage and warehousing.
- Through some analysis and collaboration with Logistics and Warehousing we moved to a larger distribution scale.
- Implemented and managed the road map for transitioning into a new system with new software.
  - o This required further collaboration with accounts, administration and sales.
  - O During the transition this required me to be decisive and listen carefully to problems and hurdles that arose.

# **Operations Manager**

Frederic's Kitchen

2009 - 2010

Navigating the liquidation and rebuild of a business has reinforced the importance of staying on top of day-to-day management, and the dangers of complacency.

## Key activity:

- **Managing the liquidation:** Working with a team of liquidators, accountants and lawyers to ensure legal compliance.
- **Restructuring:** Rebuilding the new business to be more accountable and defining clear roles & responsibilities in the leadership team.
- **Maintaining operations:** Managing the transition during the liquidation and maintaining healthy relationships with customers and suppliers to ensure business continuity.

# Book-Keeper

Frederic's Kitchen

2008-2009

This role gave me an appreciation of how to track and manage detailed finances and how important accurate fiscal management is to growth and strategic planning.

#### Front-Line Collection Officer

GE Money

2007-2008

Starting my career at a large complicated organisation gave me a solid foundation for how to use the Six Sigma framework to communicate and work within a team.

#### **SKILLS:**

#### Hard Skills:

- Effectively developed roadmaps and strategy plans
- Analysis of P&L
- Marketing

#### **Soft Skills:**

- Leadership
- Decision Making
- Collaboration & Creativity
- Communication
- Analytical Thinking
- Cross functional team collaboration

# **PASSION PROJECTS**

While running Frederic's Kitchen I have made the time to indulge my creative and entrepreneurial side. This has resulted in two revenue generating projects that are self-funding.

## **SATL Apparel**

A ski and boarding brand that produces outerwear designed for the Australian ski fields. This project was a partnership with a friend who lives at Falls Creek. It involved:

- Designing the pattern for a unique ski jacket specially built for Australian snow.
- Drawing and creating all graphics for the brand.
- Sourcing, developing and importing specific outerwear fabric from Japan.
- Working with local textile manufacturers for production.

#### **Dargo Distillery**

After applying for a Spirit Excise Licence, myself and a friend purchased a small commercial-grade still. We perfected our recipe for moonshine and gin and found a small market supplying locally produced and personalised alcohol to weddings, engagements and other events.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Product Management Course

Xi Academy 2018- currently enrolled

I'm currently enrolled in a part time (night school) Product Management course at Xi Academy. I hope this further learning will aid me bridging my current knowledge and understanding of a Product Manager and their role in a team. This course will help me understand the Agile methodology as well as be able to transition to a more refined Product Manager role.

## Diploma in Children Services

Swinburne College 2006-2007

After high school I went to TAFE to do my Diploma in Children Services to pursue a career in teaching. After I finished I was keen to get into the workforce and travel for a change.

#### High School Graduate

De La Salle 2000-2005

I completed my year 12 VCE.

**REFERENCE**: Available upon request.